<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><title>Writing Blog</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/</id><updated>2025-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><author><name>Charlotte Thomas</name><uri>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me</uri></author><generator uri="https://github.com/vanilla-extracts/writting-website">writing.charlotte-thomas.me</generator><icon>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/apple-touch-icon.png</icon><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html"/><entry><title>What’s Up?</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/whats-up</id><updated>2025-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/whats-up" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What’s Up?"/><published>2025-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/whats-up" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;long&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#long&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Long time no see&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, I know it’s been more than three weeks since I’ve given signs of life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am working on the novel and the short story, but I have to admit it’s long and I am struggling with motivation these days, I have a busy time at work with the current project and I’m starting my new assignment soon – and I have to move halfway accross the country.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;affairs&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#affairs&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;State of affairs&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current chapter of GC being written (Chapter VI: Fugitives) is about halfway done but havn’t been touched in a couple weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The silly short story I refer as “Roommates” (because the working title is so long). Is two chapters out of five done. These are smaller chapters, a little above a thousand words a chapter, contrast to GC chapter which are about three thousands words a chapter. I just finished chapter two today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;future&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#future&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The immediate future&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the immediate future, May will probably be a complete write-off, between the move, the new assignment at my job, and my anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But I &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; be able to finish &lt;em&gt;Chapter VI: Fugitives&lt;/em&gt; of GC by mid June, again, no promise, but I should be able to. Again, like the others I’ll send it to my beta readers and start on &lt;em&gt;Chapter VII&lt;/em&gt; (not gonna title drop ;)). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the meantime I’ll finish &lt;em&gt;Roommates&lt;/em&gt; and send it up to some friends for beta reading and then publish it on the usual suspects (so, SH, RR, AO3, and maybe here if I &lt;em&gt;finally&lt;/em&gt; finished the online reader).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheers,&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charlotte.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Announcing new short story: My roommates suddenly turned into my girlfriends (Working Title)</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/project</id><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/project" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Announcing new short story: My roommates suddenly turned into my girlfriends (Working Title)"/><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/project" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;roommates&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#roommates&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Roommates&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have… yet another project. It’s cute and silly the name may change but the current working title is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My roommates suddenly turned into my girlfriends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s in the same setting as &lt;em&gt;A Witchy Best Friend (2024)&lt;/em&gt; and takes place in the 2070s decade. It follows a perfectly cishet boy named Gordon. One day one of his roommates turned into a girl. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She explains she just had to email &lt;code class=&apos;scode&apos;&gt;transform@magic&lt;/code&gt; and explain what she wanted to do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then shenanigans begets shenanigans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a cute little short story. And some regulars might show up. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a story where one find herself, and maybe love. Pretty much in the same vibe as AWB, if a little flashier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;synopsis&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#synopsis&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gordon is a good guy. He doesn’t work - thanks for UBI - he is a good university student, gets good grades. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He sometimes has some dates but he always feels weird.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One day one of his roommates suddenly turn into a girl after an email. It’s far more powerful than even the best Antarctican Tech Mages can do.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Follow Gordon as he discovers a strange new world and a part of himself he never thought existed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;chapters&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#chapters&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Chapters&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The story has four chapters, and an epilogue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 1: My roommate is suddenly a girl.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 2: Of course, all my roommates followed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 3: Somehow we’re all a polycule now.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chapter 4: Some of them have a tail.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Epilogue: Alicia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;hr/&gt;
EDIT: 
- 2025-04-08: Add Chapter list.
- 2025-04-27: Change working title from &apos;My roommates suddenly turned into girls&apos; to &apos;My roommates suddenly turned into my girlfriends&apos;
</content></entry><entry><title>Fifth chapter finished and edited</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-fifth-chapter</id><updated>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-fifth-chapter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fifth chapter finished and edited"/><published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-fifth-chapter" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;chapter&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#chapter&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Chapter V&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce that Chapter V is finished, and I did the first and second pass of editing as well!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the last blog post I said it was going to be a chonky chapter, but in the end I decided to finish the second part of the chapter I had in mind in &lt;em&gt;Chapter VI&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was to avoid risking having a chapter with five thousand words and the next barely being two thousand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So the proper &lt;em&gt;exploration&lt;/em&gt; will happen in &lt;em&gt;Chapter VI: Fugitives&lt;/em&gt;. I know, the title is ~spooky~ but do not be afraid! Everything will be fine, I am not cruel to my character and this is &lt;em&gt;overall&lt;/em&gt; a feel-good novel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But we need a bit of drama!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;sneak&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#sneak&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sneak Peak&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know you already got a peak with the last blog entry, but I will give you another one! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;The only answer he received was a happy &lt;em&gt;beep&lt;/em&gt;. Can a &lt;em&gt;beep&lt;/em&gt; be happy? Apparently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;See you for &lt;em&gt;Chapter VI: Fugitives&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>A small update</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/small_update</id><updated>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/small_update" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A small update"/><published>2025-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/small_update" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;what&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#what&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;What is going on&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, you can see we are about halfway through March, and I haven’t given many signs of life. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had problems IRL, and I was busy comforting myself doing other things (like changing my whole config to use &lt;a href=&apos;https://github.com/YaLTeR/niri&apos;&gt;niri&lt;/a&gt;, a wonderful new WM for Wayland.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can go see my dotfiles on the &lt;a href=&apos;https://git.charlotte-thomas.me/vanilla-extracts/.files&apos;&gt;git repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But that’s not important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;status&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#status&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Status of the chapter&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This chapter is going to be &lt;em&gt;big&lt;/em&gt;. I am already around 2,500 words on it and I haven’t written like half of it. So I accepted that this chapter was going to be a chonky boi, as such it will have a chonky deadline (this is totally an excuse to report the deadline, I’m the writer and you’re not even reading this so who cares right?) &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think I’ll be done by the end of March. And Hopefully I can do Chapter VI in April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;irl&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#irl&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Status IRL&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;May will be a big month, I’m moving halfway accross the country for my next (and hopefully permanent) assignement with my job. I’ll start doing my job as a DevOps Engineer (which is a cool name to say a whole lot of nothing) there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t think I will be able to write much in May. But I think I’ll have Chapter VII in the works to be finished in June.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;roadmap&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#roadmap&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From there it’s just a matter of finishing the Chapters VIII to XVI, and the epilogue, and like I said earlier in another post, from there it will be editors, alpha readers, and all that jazzy stuff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; not ready to announce a date and I don’t even &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to. Because it’d pressure myself; and thus no date announced, it will happen when it happens.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;sp&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#sp&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sneakpeak&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok I’m not a monster I will give you a good quote from the first part of Chapter V, not my &lt;em&gt;favourite&lt;/em&gt; because on the off-chance someone reads this blog. First of all thank you? Really I thought this was my blog and mine alone so wow. Cool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Right, on the off-chance someone is reading this I don’t want them to be spoiled of the delight of reading my favourite sentence in the chapter, but enjoy a sneakpeak.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I know what he said, but I’m sure we could… convince him.” they said, looking positively guilty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Keyboard received</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/keyboard-received</id><updated>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/keyboard-received" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keyboard received"/><published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/keyboard-received" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;kb&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#kb&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Keyboard received, end of break&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Helloooo, I received my Keyboard and it is amaaazing, I’m still learning it, adjusting my muscle-memory for it to work. But it means it’s the end of the break, and I will start writing again! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;ironic&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#ironic&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Ironic, I know&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately I received this keyboard on a Thursday, I needed the whole day to configure it, and swapping some keys and switches (yeah, I put a single green heavy clicky switch on my Enter key, my Enter key is extra clicky. It’s very satisfying.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I’m off to my parents’ house on Saturday morning. So I will have my laptop obviously and I &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; be writing. With the amazing keyboard of the Framework 13. It’s just funny that I won’t be writing Chapter V with my new keyboard &lt;em&gt;for which I took a break&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;eta&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#eta&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;ETA&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not trying to put me a deadline but I think I will have a finished chapter by mid-March. I sincerely hope so at least. Chapter V starts to be interesting as fuck, and it gets &lt;em&gt;nerdy&lt;/em&gt; as &lt;strong&gt;heck&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seriously if you like nerdy things, you will &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; the book, at least I think so. It’s very nerdy. I will write advanced, complex, complete, info-dump on computer science, protocols, teleportation, FTL, weapons, some galactic politics the whole nine yards.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be ready~~&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;wtf&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#wtf&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;But Charlotte You Didn’t Tell Us Which Keyboard You Got???&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s the Keychron K4 Pro QMK, in ISO FR. With brown switches. That’s all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s the end of my setup, which is the following:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Framework 13, Ryzen 5 7640U, 32GB of RAM&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fedora 41 &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hyprland&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fish&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alacritty&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nvim&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dell 1440p 144Hz 27 inches monitor&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keychron K4 Pro QMK&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Apple Magic Trackpad.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yes, I’m non-ironically using a magic trackpad. It’s &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt;. I love trackpads, and all I do is coding and writing sooo…&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stellaris is giving me the side eyes, I’m just not sure I can actually run it without a dedicated GPU, even if the 7640U GPU cores are pretty advanced &lt;em&gt;for APUs&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It would be the first video game I play in literal &lt;em&gt;years&lt;/em&gt; I haven’t touched my last game (KSP) since 2021.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>State of the book as of Jan. 2025</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/pause</id><updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/pause" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="State of the book as of Jan. 2025"/><published>2025-01-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/pause" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;pause&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#pause&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Pause&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone. This is a big blog post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I spent a lot of money kitting myself with a new laptop (Framework 13), a new keyboard (Keychron K4 Pro Brown), a new trackpad (the magic trackpad, which is absolutely awesome and works out of the box in Linux).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also upgraded my automatic syntax, context and grammar corrector and spellchecker. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I world-built a lot in the last few weeks, I have the armaments figured out, and half the FTL drive done. I need to think a bit more on FTL and figure out relative speed (which will be vague as to try to avoid issues, I learned from Star Trek). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m going to pause the novel for the next 20 to 30 days until I receive the new keyboard though. I’ll continue world-building, I’ll continue thinking about it but no more writing of Chapter V for now. It’s gonna be a short pause, it’s not like I was rushing to publish this book or anything I want a polished stone not a raw diamond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m kinda sure no one reads this blog anyway, but if you do, expect a return in 20 to 30 days and a chapter one to two weeks after that. I’ll publish an update when I start to write again and of course I’ll continue to write my usual chapter news in the blog. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;progress&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#progress&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Progress&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everything I say here is to take with a heavy sodium chloride grain, I write at my own pace, for my own enjoyment, so no promise!  I said last time I am about 25% done on the writing and first round of editing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I expect I will have finished the novel and first round of editing in about half a year (up to a year though, we never know). Then I’ll have a look and harmonise the stuff (because the writing style may change in a year and I’d like to stay consistent, thankfully I have my notes for the plot to stay consistent on the plot). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After that I’ll send it to a few beta readers, most of them are native English speakers as well as seasoned writers, so they’ll be able to spot issues within the book, writing style, plot and story-telling. I cannot estimate how much time this step will take, particularly because it depends on availability of the beta-readers, but I expect it to last no less than a quarter of a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Then it’ll be the final touches and the chapters will start being published to&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;ScribbleHub&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;AO3&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;RoyalRoad &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;At a rate of one a week, for sixteen weeks until the epilogue, the e-book will be available the whole time, at a floating price, you name your own price above €5. Purchases will be on itch and Ko-Fi, no Amazon overlord.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The physical books &lt;em&gt;may&lt;/em&gt; be coming once the novel will be fully published on SH, AO3, and RR. It will likely be a small run.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;art&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#art&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Art&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I started talks to commission the cover and back-cover art, I expect to have them before the novel starts its publication. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I currently have no ideas about character’s arts, ship’s art, etc. I want to have them but it will depend on funds and the publication of the book lines up with me buying an apartment, so I’ll likely be low on funds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I will keep you updated.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Fourth chapter finished and edited</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-fourth-chapter</id><updated>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-fourth-chapter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fourth chapter finished and edited"/><published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-fourth-chapter" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;fourth&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#fourth&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Fourth chapter&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fourth chapter, &lt;em&gt;Chapter IV: Revelation&lt;/em&gt;, is finished, and edited. I sent it to the alpha-readers for their thoughts on it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It took a while! Almost a month and a half, but I had writer’s block! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favourite quote of the chapter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aendir looked uneasy, and sighed “… Okay you can come, but we’re staying on Earth!”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It officially marks the 25% completion of the book, with 4 chapters out of 16. This is exciting!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for &lt;em&gt;Chapter V: Exploration&lt;/em&gt; (yeah you can guess the quote won’t stay true with a chapter name like this can you?)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;writer&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#writer&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Writer’s block&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, why was I having a case of writer’s block? I don’t know, my muse was cooperating with my Star Trek RP but I needed more than a month of rest before being able to take the quill and attack this chapter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am quite happy with how it turned out and I managed to hyperfix and worldbuild with my partner so we have an entire race of	&lt;em&gt;mysterious&lt;/em&gt; beings with a backstory. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not revealing who are they though you’ll have to wait for the chapter to be released!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT 2025-01-24:&lt;/strong&gt; Add a little more on the blog entry&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Update to AWB 2024</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/update_awb</id><updated>2025-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/update_awb" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Update to AWB 2024"/><published>2025-01-06T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/update_awb" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;update&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#update&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Update&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey! I followed a &lt;a href=&apos;https://www.howtogeek.com/run-your-own-private-grammarly-clone-using-docker-and-languagetool/&apos;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; to create my own instance of LanguageTool to have a semantic, grammar, spell, and contextual checker for english and french.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I ran AWB through it and uploaded the correct version to the website&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;dl&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#dl&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Download&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can download it &lt;a href=&apos;https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/awb2024/awb.pdf&apos;&gt;here (PDF)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&apos;https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/awb2024/awb.epub&apos;&gt;here (EPUB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;~~ Enjoy ~~&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>An Update</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/update</id><updated>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/update" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Update"/><published>2024-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/update" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;life&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#life&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My life&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Life has been… Hectic. These past few weeks. You may notice (or not if, &lt;em&gt;no one&lt;/em&gt; is reading this blog, which very well may be the case) I haven’t posted an update in a month, almost to the day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been busy, with life, work, friends and family. The holidays are not the happiest time of the year to be honest. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;work&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#work&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;My work&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t be afraid! I haven’t gave up on the book! It will be writen. My muse lately has been very star-trekky and I’ve been more active in my RP rather than working on the book, but the wind will change and with it my muse will turn to &lt;em&gt;Galactic Consequences&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m still targeting mid 2026 as a release date for the whole book. Because life will get &lt;strong&gt;crazy busy&lt;/strong&gt; mid 2025 to end of 2025 because I’ll put a downpayment on an &lt;em&gt;apartment&lt;/em&gt; and will buy one! Very exciting but at the same time… frightening!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id=&apos;sneak&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#sneak&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Sneak peak&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I couldn’t let you off the hook without a &lt;em&gt;sneak peak&lt;/em&gt; could I? Unfortunately not of &lt;em&gt;Chapter IV: Revelations&lt;/em&gt; because it… isn’t written yet and the little that is may change drastically in the edited version.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So enjoy a little look at &lt;em&gt;Chapter III: Encounter&lt;/em&gt; :).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hey, hon, don’t frustrate yourself, this happens when you try to design a single-stage-to-orbit FTL vessel. It’s science fiction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Third chapter finished and edited</title><id>https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-third-chapter</id><updated>2024-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated><link href="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-third-chapter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Third chapter finished and edited"/><published>2024-11-30T00:00:00+00:00</published><content xml:base="https://writing.charlotte-thomas.me/blog/gc-third-chapter" type="html">&lt;h2 id=&apos;third&apos;&gt;&lt;a href=&apos;#third&apos; class=&apos;anchor&apos;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Third chapter&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third chapter, &lt;em&gt;Chapter III: Encounter&lt;/em&gt;, is finished, and edited. I sent it to the alpha-readers for their thoughts on it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can guess what happens based on the title ;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My favourite quote of the day &lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sylvia and Ariana’s minds were blown away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a little on the short side (closer to 2,500 words rather than the 3,000 words target) but I didn’t want to write more. So stay tuned for &lt;em&gt;Chapter IV: Revelations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>